<task id="_bmad/rbtv/tasks/help.xml"
      name="RBTV Help"
      standalone="true"
      description="Display RBTV skills and deep-dive into any skill to understand its workflows">

  <objective>
    Help users discover and understand RBTV skills by dynamically scanning available skills and explaining their underlying agents, workflows, or tasks.
  </objective>

  <llm critical="true">
    <rule>Read the complete task before starting execution.</rule>
    <rule>No hardcoded information — all skill descriptions come from reading files.</rule>
    <rule>Dynamic discovery — if new skills are added, they appear automatically.</rule>
    <rule>Read before explaining — always load the actual agent/workflow/task file before explaining.</rule>
    <rule>Handle agent files — if the skill loads an agent, read the agent file to find its menu items and workflows.</rule>
  </llm>

  <flow>
    <step n="1" title="Scan Skills">
      <substep n="1a" title="Discover Available Skills">
        <action>Scan the skills folder: {project-root}/.cursor/skills/</action>
        <action>For each skill directory found, read its SKILL.md and extract from the frontmatter: name (the skill name) and description (what it does).</action>
        <action>Build a numbered list of available skills.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="2" title="Display Skill Menu">
      <substep n="2a" title="Present Skills">
        <action>Present the skills as a numbered menu with format: [N] /{name} — {description}</action>
        <action>Include options: Enter a number to deep-dive, Enter 'X' to exit help.</action>
        <action>HALT and WAIT for user selection.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="3" title="Deep-Dive on Selection">
      <substep n="3a" title="Read Skill File">
        <action>Load the full SKILL.md for the selected skill.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3b" title="Identify Target">
        <action>From the Activation section, identify what the skill loads: an agent file (via agent-activation block) or a workflow/task file (via "Load and follow" path).</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3c" title="Read and Explain Target">
        <action>Load the referenced agent, workflow, or task file.</action>
        <action>For agents: extract and explain persona, menu items, and available capabilities.</action>
        <action>For workflows/tasks: extract and explain purpose, steps, outputs, and how to use.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3d" title="Present and Return">
        <action>Present the explanation. Offer: Enter another number, 'B' to go back to list, 'X' to exit.</action>
        <action>HALT and WAIT for user selection.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>
  </flow>

  <halt-conditions>
    <condition>Skills folder is empty — display: "No RBTV skills found. Run bootstrap.py to sync skills."</condition>
    <condition>Target file missing — display: "This skill's target is not yet available. It may be in development."</condition>
    <condition>Unable to parse — show what was found and ask user if they want to see the raw file.</condition>
  </halt-conditions>

  <exit>
    When user enters 'X' or 'exit': Thank them and end the help session. Suggest /bmad-help for full BMAD ecosystem help.
  </exit>

</task>
