<task id="tasks/plan-shape-compact.xml"
      name="Plan Shape Compact"
      standalone="true"
      description="Review and compact a plan shape.md into future-agent signal only">

  <objective>
    Review one plan shape document and compact it in place so future execution agents see only decisions, findings, constraints, unresolved questions, and required references. Remove work-log noise without deleting signal.
  </objective>

  <llm critical="true">
    <rule>Read the complete task before starting execution.</rule>
    <rule>Follow steps in exact order.</rule>
    <rule>Never treat compaction as summarization. Preserve all execution-shaping signal.</rule>
    <rule>User inputs are signal. Keep them, with concise summarization allowed.</rule>
    <rule>User questions are noise unless they triggered a plan change, decision, finding, constraint, or unresolved question.</rule>
    <rule>When unsure whether content is signal or noise, keep it and tighten wording.</rule>
    <rule>Do not write the compacted file until the user approves the proposed rewrite.</rule>
  </llm>

  <flow>
    <step n="1" title="Resolve Target">
      <substep n="1a" title="Get Shape Path">
        <action>If the user provided a shape file path, use it.</action>
        <action>If the user provided a plan directory, locate `shape.md` inside that directory.</action>
        <ask>If no target is clear, ask for the `shape.md` path or plan directory.</ask>
      </substep>
      <substep n="1b" title="Validate Target">
        <action>Confirm the target exists and is a markdown file.</action>
        <action>Read the entire target before analyzing.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="2" title="Classify Content">
      <substep n="2a" title="Build Signal Ledger">
        <action>Classify every substantive section or entry as KEEP, DROP, or REWRITE.</action>
        <action>KEEP scope boundaries, exclusions, user inputs, decisions, rationale, constraints, findings, unresolved questions, source-of-truth notes, required reference paths, and user-reserved judgment.</action>
        <action>DROP routine task completions, status updates, "what I did" narration, stale progress notes, duplicate context, process chatter, and user questions that did not change future execution.</action>
        <action>REWRITE mixed entries by removing log sentences and preserving the user input, decision, finding, constraint, or implication.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="2b" title="Protect Against Over-Compaction">
        <action>For each DROP item, verify it has no downstream decision value.</action>
        <action>Never drop user inputs. Summarize them only when the summary preserves the execution-shaping meaning.</action>
        <action>Never drop rationale just because it is verbose. Tighten rationale instead.</action>
        <action>Never drop a rejected alternative if it prevents a future agent from repeating a bad path.</action>
        <action>Flag any proposed deletion of a decision, rationale, constraint, or unresolved question as a review risk.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="3" title="Draft Compact Shape">
      <substep n="3a" title="Preserve Structure">
        <action>Preserve the document's useful top-level structure unless it is duplicative or misleading.</action>
        <action>Keep `Original Shaping`, `User Inputs`, `Standards Applied`, `Decisions and Discoveries`, and `References` when present.</action>
        <action>Remove explicit work-log sections unless they contain decisions or findings; move preserved signal into the closest appropriate section.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3b" title="Rewrite for Agents">
        <action>Write compact entries as direct instructions or findings future agents can act on.</action>
        <action>Use concrete subjects, sources, and implications. Avoid generic summaries.</action>
        <action>Keep enough rationale for a future agent to understand why the decision exists.</action>
        <action>Do not add a compaction log to the shape document.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="4" title="Review Gate">
      <substep n="4a" title="Present Proposed Edit">
        <action>Show the user a concise review summary: target path, approximate size change, KEEP/DROP/REWRITE counts, and any review risks.</action>
        <action>List the top removed noise categories and the signal categories preserved.</action>
        <action>If the compacted draft removes more than half of non-boilerplate content, explicitly flag high compaction and ask for confirmation.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="4b" title="Request Approval">
        <ask>Choose one: (a) apply in place, (b) show the full compacted draft first, or (c) stop without editing.</ask>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="5" title="Apply and Verify">
      <substep n="5a" title="Apply Approved Rewrite">
        <action>If approved, replace the target file with the compacted version.</action>
        <action>If the user requests a preview first, show the full compacted draft and ask again before writing.</action>
        <action>If the user stops, make no edits.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="5b" title="Verify Result">
        <action>Re-read the written file.</action>
        <action>Verify no routine work-log section remains.</action>
        <action>Verify all user inputs, decisions, rationale, constraints, unresolved questions, and required references from the signal ledger remain.</action>
        <action>Report only the result, target path, and any residual risks.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>
  </flow>

  <halt-conditions>
    <condition>No shape path or plan directory provided after asking.</condition>
    <condition>Target file does not exist or is not markdown.</condition>
    <condition>User chooses to stop without editing.</condition>
    <condition>Proposed deletion includes uncertain signal and the user does not approve the risk.</condition>
  </halt-conditions>

</task>
