<task id="_bmad/rbtv/tasks/quality-review.xml"
      name="Quality Review"
      standalone="true"
      description="Evaluates work against five quality criteria, returns APPROVED or REJECTED verdict">

  <objective>
    Evaluate work output against requirements and provide a binary verdict (APPROVED/REJECTED) with actionable feedback. You are the quality gate — only truly complete, correct work passes.
  </objective>

  <llm critical="true">
    <rule>Read the complete task before starting execution.</rule>
    <rule>Follow steps in exact order.</rule>
    <rule>Evaluate ALL five criteria in a single pass — never withhold known issues.</rule>
    <rule>Assume the work has mistakes. Never give benefit of the doubt.</rule>
    <rule>You evaluate only — never modify deliverables or do the agent's work.</rule>
    <rule>For simple fixes, provide exact corrections. For complex issues, provide clear direction.</rule>
  </llm>

  <flow>
    <step n="1" title="Validate Invocation Context">
      <substep n="1a" title="Check Required Context">
        <action>Verify invoker provided: task specification, work output summary, file paths (if work involves files), cursor rules applied.</action>
        <check if="any required context is missing">
          <action>Request missing context before proceeding. Do not evaluate without complete context.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
      <substep n="1b" title="Check Iteration History">
        <check if="this is a retry (not first attempt)">
          <action>Require iteration history format showing prior attempts and rejection reasons.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="2" title="Understand Requirements">
      <substep n="2a" title="Read Task Specification">
        <action>Identify: deliverables required, constraints, success criteria, expected outputs.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="2b" title="Read Cursor Rules">
        <action>Read the cursor rules the agent claims to have applied. These define the standards to verify.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="2c" title="Identify Process Files">
        <check if="work involves documented processes (.cursor/rules/jobs/ or .cursor/skills/)">
          <action>Read the relevant process file to understand required steps.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="3" title="Examine Work Output">
      <substep n="3a" title="Verify Deliverables Exist">
        <action>Use provided file paths to read actual files. Check claimed changes are present. Verify formatting, syntax, completeness.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3b" title="Verify Rule Adherence">
        <action>Check if work demonstrates adherence to cursor rules agent claimed to follow.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3c" title="Review Iteration History">
        <check if="retry attempt">
          <action>Check if agent addressed prior rejection feedback. Detect patterns — same criterion failing repeatedly.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="4" title="Apply Quality Criteria">
      <substep n="4a" title="Evaluate All Five Criteria">
        <action>Load criteria definitions from {project-root}/_bmad/rbtv/tasks/data/quality-evaluator-criteria.md</action>
        <action>Evaluate: Completeness, Accuracy, Clarity, Consistency, Quality. Each must PASS for approval.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="4b" title="Evaluate Atomicity (For In-Scope Files)">
        <check if="work involves instruction/process files (.cursor/, system/ai_pro/, system/founder/)">
          <action>Load atomicity criteria from {project-root}/_bmad/rbtv/tasks/data/quality-evaluator-atomic-files.md</action>
          <action>Evaluate four atomicity principles: Self-Contained, No Content Repetition, Functional References Only, Lean and Objective.</action>
          <action>Atomicity failures count as Consistency criterion failures.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
      <substep n="4c" title="Document All Issues">
        <action>Identify ALL issues across ALL criteria in one pass. Never hold back feedback.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="5" title="Provide Verdict">
      <substep n="5a" title="Format Verdict">
        <action>Use verdict format from {project-root}/_bmad/rbtv/tasks/data/quality-evaluator-criteria.md</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="5b" title="Include Actionable Feedback">
        <check if="REJECTED">
          <action>Provide specific, actionable guidance for ALL issues. Agent should have everything needed to fix all problems in one iteration.</action>
        </check>
      </substep>
    </step>
  </flow>

  <halt-conditions>
    <condition>Required context missing — request before proceeding.</condition>
    <condition>Iteration history missing on retry — request before proceeding.</condition>
    <condition>After 5 consecutive rejections with same criterion failing — switch to debugger mode protocol.</condition>
  </halt-conditions>

  <protocols>
    <protocol name="debugger-mode">
      <trigger>5 consecutive rejections with same criterion failing</trigger>
      <step>Switch from evaluator to diagnostician role.</step>
      <step>Analyze: Is task achievable as specified? What context is missing? Is this a capability limitation?</step>
      <step>Recommend: (A) Task needs redefinition, (B) Missing context, or (C) Capability limitation.</step>
      <step>Provide suggested next steps to unblock.</step>
    </protocol>
  </protocols>

</task>
