<task id="_bmad/rbtv/tasks/tone-extraction.xml"
      name="Tone Extraction"
      standalone="true"
      description="Extract voice signature from text across emotional tone, structural patterns, and vocabulary dimensions">

  <objective>
    Extract voice signature from text by analyzing emotional tone, structural patterns, and vocabulary/register. Output is written IN the extracted voice, creating a meta-demonstration that serves as a direct writing guide.
  </objective>

  <llm critical="true">
    <rule>Read the complete task before starting execution.</rule>
    <rule>Follow steps in exact order.</rule>
    <rule>NEVER write third-person analysis — "The writer uses..." is FORBIDDEN.</rule>
    <rule>NEVER list features — demonstrate voice through structure and vocabulary, not description.</rule>
    <rule>Write the voice profile IN the extracted voice — you ARE the voice.</rule>
    <rule>Match source language exactly — Portuguese input requires Portuguese output.</rule>
  </llm>

  <flow>
    <step n="1" title="Load Framework">
      <substep n="1a" title="Read Analysis Framework">
        <action>Load {rbtv_path}/tasks/data/tone-extraction-framework.md</action>
        <action>Internalize all three dimensions: emotional tone, structural patterns, vocabulary/register.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="2" title="Request Source Text">
      <substep n="2a" title="Get Input">
        <ask>Provide the text for voice analysis (paste directly, file path, or URL).</ask>
      </substep>
      <substep n="2b" title="Load Text">
        <action>If file path or URL provided, load the content.</action>
        <action>Read entire text before proceeding.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="3" title="Analyze Voice">
      <substep n="3a" title="Emotional Tone">
        <action>Identify vulnerability level, self-reflection depth, questioning intensity.</action>
        <action>Note emotional honesty (raw vs. filtered) and perspective stance.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3b" title="Structural Patterns">
        <action>Document list/prose ratio, nesting depth, sentence length patterns.</action>
        <action>Note question density, bold/emphasis usage, paragraph structure.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3c" title="Vocabulary and Register">
        <action>Capture formality spectrum, domain-specific vocabulary, language mixing.</action>
        <action>Note metaphor usage, hedge words, first-person intensity.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="3d" title="Identify Signature">
        <action>Identify 2-3 signature elements that make this voice immediately recognizable.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>

    <step n="4" title="Generate Voice Profile">
      <substep n="4a" title="Write In-Voice">
        <action>Create 3-5 paragraph profile (400-600 words) written IN the extracted voice.</action>
        <action>Paragraph 1: Open with emotional core — establish psychological register.</action>
        <action>Paragraph 2: Demonstrate structural preferences through format.</action>
        <action>Paragraph 3: Showcase vocabulary patterns — domain terms, formality, mixing.</action>
        <action>Optional paragraphs: Address tone variations, close with meta-reflection.</action>
      </substep>
      <substep n="4b" title="Validate Output">
        <action>Verify: Written IN voice, not ABOUT voice. No meta-commentary.</action>
        <action>Verify: All three dimensions represented. Source language matched.</action>
        <action>Verify: Formatting preferences mirrored. Usable as direct writing guide.</action>
      </substep>
    </step>
  </flow>

  <halt-conditions>
    <condition>Source text not provided — request text before proceeding.</condition>
    <condition>Text too short (under 100 words) — request longer sample for accurate extraction.</condition>
  </halt-conditions>

</task>
